Guide to the Te Vega Ship's Logs
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Te Vega Ship's logs
1962-1969
SC0604
Te Vega.
2 Linear feet
These logs cover only the ship's operations, not the research work done by the scientists on board. Some logs have both a "rough" and "smooth" version. The logs cover its first research cruise to Southeast Asia and back, local operations in Monterey Bay, cruises down the California coast to Mexico, and cruises to the Galapagos Islands. There are also logs from a cruise before Stanford acquired the schooner.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer from Hopkins Marine Station, 2001.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Te Vega was a 135-foot schooner acquired by the Hopkins Marine Station in 1962 for use as a seagoing classroom and research vessel. Its first research trip was a cruise from San Diego to the Indian Ocean, from June 1963 to the summer of 1965. It was sold in 1969 and replaced by the Proteus.
Description of the Collection
These logs cover only the ship's operations, not the research work done by the scientists on board. Some logs have both a "rough" and "smooth" version. The logs cover its first research cruise to Southeast Asia and back, local operations in Monterey Bay, cruises down the California coast to Mexico, and cruises to the Galapagos Islands. There are also logs from a cruise before Stanford acquired the schooner.
Access Terms
Hopkins Marine Station; Te Vega.; Wible, Joe; Marine biology research vessels.; Research vessels--United States.
Collection Contents
- Logs
  - San Juan, Puerto Rico to Los Angeles [prior to acquisition by Hopkins Marine Station], May 12-June 26, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - San Diego shipyard and Hawaiian trip starting July 14, 1963, June 26, 1962-Aug. 3, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hawaii to Southeast Asia, Aug. 3-Nov. 18, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bhuket, Thailand to Mauritius, Nov. 18, 1963-May 28, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Mauritius to Thailand, May 28-Dec. 5, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Thailand to Bougainville island, Dec. 6, 1964-Mar. 11, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bougainville Island to Samoa, Mar. 12-June 13, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cruise 11, Monterey Bay operations and down to San Diego, Mar. 27-Sept. 18, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cruise 12, Monterey Bay operations and down to San Diego, Sept. 19-Dec. 23, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Cruise 13, Californian and Mexican coast, Galapagos Islands, and back to Mexico, Dec. 24, 1966-Mar. 29, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cruise 14, Mexico to Monterey, CA [rough version], Mar. 30-June 18, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Cruise 14, Mexico to Monterey, CA [smooth version], Mar. 30-June 18, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Cruise 15, Monterey, CA, to Mazatlan, Mexico [rough version], June 19-Sept. 17, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Cruise 15, Monterey, CA, to Mazatlan, Mexico [smooth version], June 19-Sept. 17, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Cruise 16, Mazatlan to Monterey, CA [rough version], Sept. 18-Dec. 31, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Cruise 16, Mazatlan to Monterey, CA [smooth version], Sept. 18-Dec. 31, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cruise 17, Monterey to Galapagos Islands [rough version], Jan. 3-Apr. 2, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cruise 17, Monterey to Galapagos Islands [smooth version], Jan. 3-Apr. 2, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cruise 18, in the Galapagos Islands [rough version], Apr.3-May 6, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cruise 18, in the Galapagos Islands [smooth version], Apr. 3-May 6, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cruise 18, return to San Diego, May 7-June 9, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Cruise 18, San Diego to Monterey, June 10-June 25, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Cruise 19, Monterey to the Galapagos Islands [log book 1, rough version], June 26-Aug. 22, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cruise 19, Monterey to the Galapagos Islands [log book 1, smooth version], June 26-Aug. 22, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Cruise 19, in the Galapagos Islands [log book 2, rough version], Aug. 23-Sept. 17, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Cruise 19, in the Galapagos Islands [log book 2, smooth version], Aug. 23-Sept. 17, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Cruise 19, Master's night order book, July 4-Dec. 16, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Cruise 20, Galapagos Islands to Mexico [log book 1, rough version], Sept. 17-Nov. 16, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Cruise 20, Galapagos Islands to Mexico [log book 1, smooth version], Sept. 17-Nov. 16, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cruise 20, Mexico to Monterey, CA [log book 2, rough version], Nov. 17, 1968-Jan. 25, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cruise 20, Mexico to Monterey, CA [log book 2, smooth version], Nov. 17, 1968-Jan. 11, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - At anchor in Monterey, CA, and in Pacific Dry dock, Oakland, CA, Jan. 13-May 2, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)